Woodrow Wilson Collection, 1837-1986 (bulk 1883-1924 ): Preliminary Finding Aid MC168
Public Policy Papers
- Series 5: Memorabilia, 1879-1935; 2 boxes
  The Memorabilia Series maintains the organization given to it as new items were aquired.
  - Undergraduate years, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Wilson, Woodrow, Princeton presidency, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - Wilson, Woodrow, U.S. presidency, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous reunions, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - Dinner to honor Wilson, 1897 March 12; 1 folder (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - Directories, 1930-1935; 1 folder (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - A History of the Class of '79, Godwin, H (autographed by Wilson), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - The Class of 1879 Princeton College, 1879-1894, 1 folder (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - Quindecennial Record, printed, not published, 1894; 1 folder (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - Memorabilia-Princeton University, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - Wilson, Woodrow, Governor of New Jersey, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - Wilson, Woodrow, presidential years, 1913-1920; 1 folder (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - Wilson, Woodrow, presidential campaign, 1912; 1 folder (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - Wilson, Woodrow, post cards-foreign, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 45, Folder 6)
- Series 6: Ephemera, 1956; 1 box
  The Ephemera Series includes booklets, pamphlets, and articles and other items on the Wilson Centennial in 1956, Wilson tributes and campaign materials, and information from the Woodrow Wilson Foundation.
  The Ephemera Series maintains the organization given to it as new items were aquired.
  - Wilson, Woodrow, Centennial, 1956; 1 folder (Box 45, Folder 7)
  - Memorial tributes, undated; 1 folder (Box 45, Folder 8)
  - Presidential campaign material, undated; 1 folder (Box 45, Folder 9)
  - Princeton University, undated; 1 folder (Box 45, Folder 10)
  - Wilson, Woodrow, foundation, undated; 1 folder (Box 45, Folder 11)
  - General, undated; 1 folder (Box 45, Folder 12)
- Series 7: Non-Print Media, undated; 1 box
  The Non-Print Media Series includes audiovisual and sound recordings on Wilson: Howard L. Hughes' "Recollections of Woodrow Wilson," a sound filmstrip on "Woodrow Wilson: Idealism and American Democracy," and a record of Wilson speeches on "Labor" and "The Tarrif."
  The Non-Print Media Series is arranged by form and size.
  - Tape Recording, "Recollections of Woodrow Wilson by Howard L. Hughes" AM 19398, undated; 1 box (Box 45)
    (See Oversized Box 113)
  - Sound Filmstrip, "Woodrow Wilson: Idealism and American Democracy," AM 19449, undated; 1 box (Box 45)
  - Record, Addresses on "Labor" and 'The Tariff" AM 18105, undated; 1 box (Box 45)
- Series 8: Miscellaneous Material, undated; 1 box
  The Miscellaneous Material Series is comprised of envelopes to the letters of Woodrow and Ellen Axson Wilson.
  The Miscellaneous Material Series is arranged chronologically.
  - Envelopes to the letters of Wilson, Woodrow and Wilson, Ellen Axson, undated; 1 box (Box 46)
- Series 9: Printed Matter, 1876-1956; 2 boxes
  The Printed Matter Series consists of printed matter by and about Woodrow Wilson, mainly printed addresses, speeches, and cartoons in newspaper and printed forms.
  The Printed Matter Series contains several sections including: Other than Newspapers, which is divided into By Wilson and About Wilson, and arranged alphabetically by title; Newspapers and Clippings, arranged alphabetically; and Oversized, arranged by size.
  - Other than Newspapers, 1902 December 9-1919 July 10; 1 box
    - By Wilson, Woodrow, 1902 December 9-1919 July 10; 1 box
      - "Achievement vs. Evasion" speech, 1916 September 30; 1 folder (Box 47, Folder 1)
      - Address at the laying of the cornerstone of the Central Presbyterian Church, 1913 December 19; 1 folder (Box 47, Folder 2)
      - Address before the Southern Commercial Congress, 1913 October 27; 1 folder (Box 47, Folder 3)
      - Address of Welcome to the eighteenth annual Convention of the Association of Colleges and Preparatory Schools of the Middle States and Maryland, at Princeton, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 47, Folder 4)
      - Address to the Senate regarding: Peace treaty and League of Nations, 1919 July 10; 1 folder (Box 47, Folder 5)
      - Address delivered to a joint session of Congress, 1917 December 4; 1 folder (Box 47, Folder 6)
      - "Die Note des Prasidenten Wilson", 2 copies (in German) note dropped in Daun, Germany, 1918 October 23; 1 folder (Box 47, Folder 7)
      - Excerpt from "Spirit of Learning" address at Harvard, 1909; 1 folder (Box 47, Folder 8)
      - "Law and Order Patriotism," a statement, 1918 July 26; 1 folder (Box 47, Folder 9)
      - Letter to Chariman Doremus of the Democratic National Congressional Comm, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 47, Folder 10)
      - Letter read at Newark, N.J., 1918 March 20; 1 folder (Box 47, Folder 11)
      - Letter to "My Fellow Countrymen", 1918 October 25; 1 folder (Box 47, Folder 12)
      - Message to the Congress regarding: War, 1917 April 2; 1 folder (Box 47, Folder 13)
      - "Politics" (from dictation), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 47, Folder 14)
      - "Princeton for the Nation's Service" (2 copies), 1903; 1 folder (Box 47, Folder 15)
      - Proclamation, "Red Cross Week" the week beginning, 1918 May 20; 1918 May 4; 1 folder (Box 47, Folder 16)
      - "Rede des Prasidenten Wilson", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 47, Folder 17)
      - "Responsible Government under the Constitution", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 47, Folder 18)
      - Speech at Princeton dinner, 1902 December 9; 1 folder (Box 47, Folder 19)
      - Speech delivered by Wilson, Woodrow, College Men's League dinner, 1912 September 28; 1 folder (Box 47, Folder 20)
      - Statement on Mexican affairs, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 47, Folder 21)
      - Addresses while Governor of New Jersey, 1910-1912; 1 folder (Box 47, Folder 22)
    - About Wilson, Woodrow, dates not examined; 1 box
      - Specific AM number, "Le President Wilson a la Sorbonne", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 47, Folder 23)
      - Pamphlets, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 47, Folder 24)
      - Photographs "A History of the American", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 47, Folder 25)
      - Miscellaneous, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 47, Folder 26)
      - People advertisement, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 47, Folder 26)
      - "Bibliography-Wilson, Woodrow, 1917-1921", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 47, Folder 26)
      - "Ecce homo" cartoon, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 47, Folder 26)
      - "Woodrow Wilson: Living Martyr", dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 47, Folder 26)
  - Newspapers and Clippings (Oversized), 1924-1956; 1 box
    - Cartoons (not in Wilson scrapbook), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 48, Folder 1)
    - Cartoons (1913-1921), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 48, Folder 2)
    - Regarding Centennial of Wilson, Woodrow's birth, 1956; 1 folder (Box 48, Folder 3)
    - Regarding The True Story of Woodrow Wilson by Lawrence, David, serialized in the Ohio State Journal, Columbus, 1924; 1 folder (Box 48, Folder 4)
    - General, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 48, Folder 5)
  - Oversized Printed Matter, 1876-1918; 1 box
    (See Oversized Box 108 and 111)
    - The New York Times, 1914-1918 Gift of Mr. Richard R. Lytle Class of 1876, 1 box (Box 48)
    - Harper's Weekly, "The New President of Princeton,", 1902 June 21; 1 box (Box 48)
    - Newspapers (Miscellaneous), dates not examined; 1 box (Box 48)
    - Miscellaneous Printed Matter (2 items), dates not examined; 1 box (Box 48)
    - Framed Wilson Address from New York Times, 1917 April 3; 1 box (Box 48)
- Series 10: Papers of Others About Woodrow Wilson, 1837-1986 October 14; 58 boxes; 2 folders
  The Papers of Others About Woodrow Wilson Series consists of groups of papers collected by others about Woodrow Wilson. The collectors include writings, correspondence, documents, and photos collection by family (Stockton Axson, Eleanor Wilson McAdoo, and Margaret Wilson), along with writings such as reminiscences, theses, or dissertations on Wilson and correspondence collections on Wilson (Wilson Farrand, McMillan Lewis, William McCombs). Also included in this series is the Henry Bragdon Collection of Reminiscences (made up of interviews and correspondence on Wilson), papers of Laura Turnbull, the Curator of the Woodrow Wilson Collection, on her work for Woodrow Wilson: A Selected Bibliography of his Writings, Addresses, and Public Papers, and some files of the Woodrow Wilson Foundation. Finally, the series includes the papers of Charles L. Swem, Wilson's stenographic secretary, including shorthand notebooks, transcriptions of speeches, correspondence, and interviews recorded from 1912-1921, as well as photographs, and documents, divided into sections on Wilson and on personal topics, and a collection of newspaper clipping scrapbooks on Wilson from the Woodrow Wilson Foundation and individuals.
  The Papers of Others About Woodrow Wilson Series is broken down into multiple sections based on the collector or creator of the papers. Within each section, materials are organized by form and then alphabetically.
  - Family, 1837-1962; 4 boxes; 2 folders
    - Works, 1915-1962; 1 box
      - Axson, Stockton, 1915; 1 box
        - "April the Second, 1917," TMs, Axson, Stockton, undated; 1 folder (Box 49, Folder 1)
        - "It was in the year 1883," AMs, undated; 1 folder (Box 49, Folder 2)
        - "Marion (Alabama) Institute Dedication Woodrow Wilson stained Glass Windows," AMs Outline, Undated, TMs, Undated, AMs, Undated, TMs, incomplete, Undated, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 49, Folder 3)
        - "Mr. Wilson: An Appreciation and a Bit of Analysis" TMs, Undated, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 49, Folder 4)
        - "President Wilson and the Soldier" AMs, undated; 1 folder (Box 49, Folder 5)
        - "The Practical Idealism of Woodrow Wilson" TMs, undated; 1 folder (Box 49, Folder 6)
        - "The University Lecturer" AMs, undated; 1 folder (Box 49, Folder 7)
        - Lecture Notes: "Early Colonial literature in New England" AMs, undated; 1 folder (Box 49, Folder 8)
        - Lecture Notes: "Woodrow Wilson as Man of Letters" AMs, undated; 1 folder (Box 49, Folder 9)
        - Letter to Editor: "To the Editor of ..." AMsS, circa 1915; undated; 1 folder (Box 49, Folder 9A)
      - McAdoo, Eleanor Wilson, 1929-1962; 1 box
        - "A Honeymoon Trip to Princeton, N. J." TMsS, Axson, Margaret Callaway (Mrs. Benjamin Palmer Axson), 1929; 1 folder (Box 49, Folder 10)
        - The Priceless Gift, McGraw Hill, galley proofs (contains correspondence between Wilson, Woodrow, and Wilson, Ellen Axson), 1962; 1 folder (Box 49, Folder 11)
        - Ams of funeral oration spoken at her funeral. Brown, L. C. (Brown, Laura C. Hoyt), and Brown, Warren A. (Mrs.), (aunt of Wilson, Ellen Axson), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 49, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence, 1837-1960; 2 boxes
      - ALS to Brown, Louisa C. Hoyt (Mrs. Warren A. Brown) Axson, Edward William, 1884; 1 folder (Box 50, Folder 1)
      - ALS to Brown, Louisa C. Hoyt (Mrs. Warren A. Brown) Axson, Edward William, 1889; 1 folder (Box 50, Folder 2)
      - ACS to Wilson, Ellen Axson Axson, Margaret Callaway (Mrs. B. Palmer Axson), undated; 1 folder (Box 50, Folder 3)
      - 5 AlsS to Axson, Samuel Edward. Axson, Margaret Jane Hoyt (Mrs. Samuel Edward Axson), 1860-1861; 1 folder (Box 50, Folder 4)
      - ALS to Brown, Louisa C. Hoyt her sister. Axson, Margaret Jane Hoyt (Mrs. Samuel Edward Axson), 1880; 1 folder (Box 50, Folder 5)
      - TL (copy) to Mr. McMahon. Axson, Margaret Randolph, 1910; 1 folder (Box 50, Folder 6)
      - ALS to Barnes, J.R. (Ms.), (transcript included), 1903; 1 folder (Box 50, Folder 7)
      - ALS to Brown, Louisa C. Hoyt (Mrs. Warren A. Brown) Axson, Randolph, 1890; 1 folder (Box 50, Folder 8)
      - 5 AlsS to Brown, Louisa C. Hoyt (Mrs. Warren A. Brown) Axson, Rebecca L (Mrs. Isaac Stockton Keith Axson), circa 1882-1894; 1 folder (Box 50, Folder 9)
      - ALS to her son Axson, Isaac Stockton Keith. Axson, S. A. (Mrs.), 1837; 1 folder (Box 50, Folder 10)
      - 5 AlsS to his wife Axson, Margaret Jane Hoyt. Axson, Samuel Edward, 1839-1859; 1 folder (Box 50, Folder 11)
      - 4 AlsS to Brown, Louisa C. Hoyt (Mrs. Warren A. Brown) Axson, Samuel E, 1880-1883; 1 folder (Box 50, Folder 12)
      - 25 AcsS to Brown, Louisa C. Hoyt (Mrs. Warren A. Brown) Axson, Samuel Edward, 1881-1883; 1 folder (Box 50, Folder 13)
      - ALS to Axson, George M. Priest, Stockton, 1920; 1 folder (Box 50, Folder 14)
      - 3 AlsS to Axson, Benjamin M. King, Stockton, 1913-1914; 1 folder (Box 50, Folder 15)
      - 2 AlsS to Axson, Benjamin M. King, Stockton, 1914; 1 folder (Box 50, Folder 16)
      - ALS to Axson, Margaret Callaway (Mrs. Palmer Axson) Axson, Stockton, 1914; 1 folder (Box 50, Folder 17)
      - ALS to Brown, Louisa C. Hoyt (Mrs. Warren A. Brown) (transcript included), 1906; 1 folder (Box 50, Folder 18)
      - 4 AlsS to Osgood, Charles G, 1914-1922; 1 folder (Box 50, Folder 19)
      - ACS to Mrs. Cogswell Bolling, Bertha, undated; 1 folder (Box 50, Folder 20)
      - TLS to Bolling, Kate Trenholm Abrams, John Randolph, 1927; 1 folder (Box 50, Folder 21)
      - ACS to Cogswell, William (Mrs.), Bolling S. W, 1915; 1 folder (Box 50, Folder 22)
      - ALS to Smith, M.B., (Mrs.), Bones, Helen Woodrow, 1913; 1 folder (Box 50, Folder 23)
      - ACS to Smith, M.B., (Mrs.), 1917; 1 folder (Box 50, Folder 23)
      - ACS to Smith, M.B., (Mrs.), signed by Hager, Isabella L., Wilson, Ellen Axson's, secretary, (xeroxes and typescripts included), 1913; 1 folder (Box 50, Folder 23)
      - 9 ALsS, 1 TLS [1913] to Brower, Jessie Woodrow Bones, her sister Bones, Helen Woodrow, 1 folder (Box 50, Folder 24)
      - 4 ALsS [1913] to Axson, Margaret Calloway, Bones, Helen Woodrow, 1914; 1 folder (Box 50, Folder 25)
      - 3 ALsS to Brown, Mary Celestine Mitchell (Mrs. Edward T. Brown), 1916-1917; 1 folder (Box 50, Folder 26)
      - 4 ALsS to Vreeland, Williamson V. (Mrs.), Bones, Helen Woodrow, 1913-1916; 1 folder (Box 50, Folder 27)
      - ALS to King, Benjamin M., transcript included, Bones, Helen Woodrow, 1918; 1 folder (Box 50, Folder 28)
      - ALS to King, Benjamin M., Helen Woodrow, 1913; 1 folder (Box 50, Folder 29)
      - ALS unidentified correspondent, 1914; 1 folder (Box 50, Folder 30)
      - AL (fragment) unidentified correspondent, undated; 1 folder (Box 50, Folder 30)
      - ALS by Loft, Helen H. printed card invitation. Letters to Bones, Helen Wilson, undated; 1 folder (Box 50, Folder 30)
      - TL (copy) to Mr. Foresman Bower, Jessie B, undated; 1 folder (Box 50, Folder 31)
      - 3 ALsS to his wife Brown, Mary Celestine Mitchell, Brown, Edward Thomas, 1915; 1 folder (Box 50, Folder 32)
      - Telegram to Smith, M.B., (Mrs.), 1925; 1 folder (Box 50, Folder 33)
      - ALS to Axson, Margaret Randolph. Brown, Louisa C. Hoyt (Mrs. Warren A. Brown), 1889; 1 folder (Box 50, Folder 34)
      - Telegram printed invitation Brown, Marjorie (Mrs. Benjamin King), 1917; 1 folder (Box 50, Folder 35)
      - 5 ALsS to Brown, H. S. Mitchell (Mrs.), Mitchell, Mary Celestine, 1916-1917; 1 folder (Box 50, Folder 36)
      - ALS to Axson, Benjamin Palmer Elliot, Axson, Margare,t (Mrs. Edward G. Elliot), 1938; 1 folder (Box 50, Folder 37)
      - 9 ALsS to Axson, Margaret Calloway, 1939-1947; 1 folder (Box 50, Folder 38)
      - ALS to Barnes, T. R., (Mrs.), (typescript included) Ewing, Robert, 1905; 1 folder (Box 50, Folder 39)
      - ALS to Thackwell, Helen Welles Howe, Annie Wilson (sister of Wilson, Woodrow), undated; 1 folder (Box 50, Folder 40)
      - 1 ALS, 1 AL (fragment) to Mitchell, H. S., (Mrs.), (Mrs. Benjamin King), 1916; 1 folder (Box 50, Folder 41)
      - McAdoo family correspondence McAdoo, William Gibbs (husband of Wilson, Eleanor Randolph), 1854-1869; 1 folder (Box 50, Folder 42)
      - 5 letters to him regarding the presidential election of 1912 March 25-28including: TLS by Stovall, Pleasant A., 1912 and ALS by Glass, Frank P., 1912, 1 folder (Box 50, Folder 43)
      - ALS to Brown, Louisa C. Hoyt (Mrs. Warren A. Brown) McDonald, M. L, 1881; 1 folder (Box 50, Folder 44)
      - ALS to Axson, Nell. Sayre, Eleanor, 1929; 1 folder (Box 50, Folder 45)
      - TLS to Axson, Nell telegram with ANS. Sayre, Francis Bowes, 1933; 1929; 1 folder (Box 50, Folder 46)
      - 4 TLsS to Axson, Margaret Callaway (Mrs. Benjamin Palmer Axson) Sayre, Francis Bowes, 1915-1939; 1 folder (Box 50, Folder 47)
      - ALS to Thackwell, Helen Welles, Sayre, Jessie Woodrow Wilson, 1916; 1 folder (Box 51, Folder 1)
      - 13 ALsS to Axson, Margaret Callaway (Mrs. Benjamin Palmer Axson), 1913-1932; 1 folder (Box 51, Folder 2)
      - 2 ALsS to Bremer, Althea, circa 1915-1916; 1 folder (Box 51, Folder 3)
      - 2 AlsS to King, Marjorie (Mrs. Benjamin King), 1932; 1 folder (Box 51, Folder 4)
      - 2 ALsS to Vreeland, Williamson V. (Mrs.), 1913-1915; 1 folder (Box 51, Folder 5)
      - 2 ALsS to King, Benjamin M, 1912-1915; 1 folder (Box 51, Folder 6)
      - 2 ALsS to Axson, Nell, 1928-1929; 1 folder (Box 51, Folder 7)
      - ALS to Axson, Benjamin Palmer, 1927; 1 folder (Box 51, Folder 8)
      - 2 ALsS to King, Benjamin M.; Smith, Mary, 1916; 1 folder (Box 51, Folder 9)
      - 2 ALsS to King, Benjamin M.; Smith, Mary, 1916; 1 folder (Box 51, Folder 10)
      - ALS by Welles, Harriet Woodrow (her mother); Thackwell, Helen Welles, 1913; 1 folder (Box 51, Folder 11)
      - ALS to Brown, Mary Celestine Mitchell (Mrs. Edward T. Brown); Wilson, Edith Bolling, 1916; 1 folder (Box 51, Folder 12)
      - TL (copy) to Brophy, Alice A., [1924], undated; 1 folder (Box 51, Folder 13)
      - TL (copy) by Brophy, Alice A. to Mrs. Wilson, 1924; 1 folder (Box 51, Folder 13)
      - 4 TLsS to Newham, Edward (letters signed by her secretaries) card with Wilson's picture. Wilson, Edith Bolling, 1933; 1951; 1 folder (Box 51, Folder 14)
      - ALS to [Thomas], Helen, 1925; 1 folder (Box 51, Folder 15)
      - ACS to Thomas, S. Seymour, undated; 1 folder (Box 51, Folder 15)
      - ALS to King, Marjorie (Mrs. Benjamin King), 1960; 1 folder (Box 51, Folder 16)
      - ALS to Brown, Marjorie (Mrs. Benjamin King), Wilson, Edith Bolling, 1942; 1 folder (Box 51, Folder 17)
      - ALS to Huntington, (Mrs.), 1929; 1 folder (Box 51, Folder 18)
      - TLS to Fortunato, Vladimir, 1924; 1 folder (Box 51, Folder 19)
      - 8 TLsS to Abrams, Kate Trenholm, 1924-1931; 1 folder (Box 51, Folder 20)
      - 6 ALsS to Abrams, Kate Trenholm, 1919-1930; 1 folder (Box 51, Folder 20)
      - 2 cards to Abrams, Kate Trenholm, 1924; 1 folder (Box 51, Folder 20)
      - TLS to Marshall, Thomas R, 1919; 1 folder (Box 51, Folder 21)
      - ALS to Marshall, Thomas R., [1919], dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 51, Folder 21)
      - 1 TLS by Dodge, Cleveland H, 1924; 1 folder (Box 51, Folder 22)
      - 1 ALS by Jaffray, Elizabeth, undated; 1 folder (Box 51, Folder 22)
      - 3 ALsS to Thackwell, Helen, Wilson, Eleanor Randolph (Mrs. William G. McAdoo), 1914-1917; 1 folder (Box 51, Folder 23)
      - 2 ALsS to Wilson, Ellen Axson her mother, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 51, Folder 24)
      - 2 typescripts of letters to Clark, John Bates. Wilson, Ellen Axson, 1897; 1 folder (Box 51, Folder 25)
      - ALS to Axson, Margaret Callaway (Mrs. Benjamin Palmer Axson). Walker, Ellen Axson, 1913; 1 folder (Box 51, Folder 26)
      - Typescript of letter to Fine, May. Wilson, Ellen Axson, 1913; 1 folder (Box 51, Folder 27)
      - 17 ALsS to Harris, Anna, 1885-1912; 1 folder (Box 51, Folder 28)
      - ALS (Photostat) to Howe, (Mr.), 1913; 1 folder (Box 51, Folder 29)
      - ALS to Axson, Margaret Randolph (sister), 1887; 1 folder (Box 51, Folder 30)
      - 2 ALsS to Brown, Louisa C. Hoyt (Mrs. Warren A. Brown), 1890; 1906; 1 folder (Box 51, Folder 31)
      - ALS to "My dear Alice", 1905; 1 folder (Box 51, Folder 32)
      - ALS (fragment) (transcripts included), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 51, Folder 32)
      - 5 ALsS to Brown, Mary Celestine Mitchell (Mrs. Edward T. Brown). Wilson, Ellen Axson, 1908-1910; 1 folder (Box 51, Folder 33)
      - 1 ALS to Bones, Helen, 1912; 1 folder (Box 51, Folder 34)
      - 1 ACS to Bones, Helen, undated; 1 folder (Box 51, Folder 34)
      - 2 ALsS to Brown, Mary Celestine Mitchell (Mrs. Edward T. Brown), 1911-1912; 1 folder (Box 51, Folder 35)
      - 2 ALsS to "Mimmi," Smith, M. B., (Mrs.), (transcripts included), 1912; 1 folder (Box 51, Folder 36)
      - ALS to Erwin, Mary A, 1902; 1 folder (Box 51, Folder 37)
      - ALS to Anderson, Mary, 1912; 1 folder (Box 51, Folder 38)
      - ALS to Fielder, J. W., Junior, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 51, Folder 39)
      - 5 ALsS to King, Benjamin M, 1912-1914; 1 folder (Box 51, Folder 40)
      - 15 ALsS to Axson, Margaret Callaway (Mrs. Benjamin Palmer Axson), 1908-1913; 1 folder (Box 51, Folder 41)
      - 1 ALS by Weller, Charles F, 1913; 1 folder (Box 51, Folder 42)
      - 1 ALS by Wilson, Nathaniel, undated; 1 folder (Box 51, Folder 42)
      - ALS (Photostat) to "My dear brother". Wilson, Jeannie (Woodrow Wilson's mother), 1865; 1 folder (Box 51, Folder 43)
      - ALS (Photostat) to "My dearest brother". Wilson, Joseph Ruggles, undated; 1 folder (Box 51, Folder 44)
      - ACS to Vreeland, Williamson V. (Mrs.), Wilson, Margaret Woodrow; [1914], dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 51, Folder 45)
      - TLS to Seeley, Walter H, undated; 1 folder (Box 51, Folder 46)
      - 1 TLS to Axson, Ellen, 1919; 1 folder (Box 51, Folder 47)
      - 1 TLS to Axson, Ellen, and her brother Axson, Benjamin Palmer, 1920; 1 folder (Box 51, Folder 47)
      - 1 telegram to Axson, Ellen and Axson, Benjamin Palmer, 1920; 1 folder (Box 51, Folder 47)
      - 3 ALsS to King, Benjamin M, 1912-1916; 1 folder (Box 51, Folder 48)
      - 1 TLS, [1916], dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 51, Folder 48)
      - 8 ALsS to Axson, Margaret Callaway (Mrs. Benjamin Palmer Axson), 1917-1934; 1 folder (Box 51, Folder 50)
      - 2 TLsS to Axson, Margaret Callaway, 1918; 1935; 1 folder (Box 51, Folder 50)
      - 1 Telegram to Axson, Margaret Callaway, 1918; 1 folder (Box 51, Folder 50)
      - To "Dear Lucy" unidentified, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 51, Folder 51)
    - Documents, 1896-1897; 1 box
      - 4 school reports Axson, Margaret Randolph, 1896-1897; 1 folder (Box 52, Folder 1)
    - Photographs, 1905-1917; 1 box
      - 2 photoraphs, Axson, Edward, William, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 52, Folder 2)
      - Photograph, Axson, Stockton, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 52, Folder 3)
      - Photograph, Axson, Mrs. Isaac Stockton Keith, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 52, Folder 3a)
      - Photograph Axson, Isaac Stockton Keith II, 1917; 1 folder (Box 52, Folder 4)
      - Photograph Axson, Margaret (Mrs. Edward G. Elliot), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 52, Folder 5)
      - Photograph, Bones, Helen Woodrow, dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 52, Folder 6)
      - 2 photographs, Brown, Marjorie (Mrs. Benjamin King), 1910; 1 folder (Box 52, Folder 7)
      - Photograph, Brown, Warren A. and Mrs. Brown (Louisa C. Hoyt), 1905; 1 folder (Box 52, Folder 8)
      - Photograph Brown, Warren A. and Baby Axson, Edward Jr, 1905; 1 folder (Box 52, Folder 9)
      - Photograph Cothran, Annie Howe and Josephine (niece of Woodrow Wilson), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 52, Folder 10)
      - Photograph Hoyt, Margaret Jane (Mrs. Edward Axson), dates not examined; 1 folder (Box 52, Folder 11)